♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Now, let's see.
Wow! Unbelievable!
Come on, Jeremie, let's get a move on!
Otherwise, there won't be
any hot water left.
Hey, remember The Hermitage?
You mean the house where
Aelita had those visions?
Bad memory, Jeremie.
Right. Well, I wanted to
check it out a little closer,
and I found out something amazing!
What would really be amazing
Is if there are still some eggs left
when we get down to breakfast!
Odd, you're a real walking stomach,
you know that?
And you're a walking brain!
You see? We compliment each other!
I did a little research to find out
who that old house belonged to,
and I came across a restricted access site.
It took me most of the night to hack into it,
but it was worth it!
I found a deed signed
by a Mr. Franz Hopper.
Seems that he's the owner.
And do you think it has
something to do with Lyoko?
Ulrich, there's a secret
underground passage
into the sewers from
his yard, believe it or not,
so the guy must've had something
to do with the supercomputer!
Exactly.
So, I did a search on
Franz Hopper, and guess what.
He was a science teacher
right here at Kadic Academy.
Is that weird or what!
(WEARY CHATTER)
Ha!
Finally! It's about time!
Every morning, it's the same thing!
Yeah. But things might start
moving now that Sissi's done.
Shut up, kiddies!
Poor thing!
You'll be here for
another two hours!
Why not go upstairs?
There's some showers free up there,
and not a girl in sight.
(CLAMORING)
The girl's showers
are downstairs, Aelita!
Aelita Stones! Hey!
what do you think you're doing here?
Please go easy on her, Jim.
She's new here.
Right. Well, new or not,
a young lady has no business
in the boy's showers.
But I-I thought that--
I don't want to hear your excuses!
Pull that again, and you go
straight to the principal's office!
Hmph!
Well, Miss Einstein,
it's just like I said, huh.
Not a single girl
in these showers.
Sissi, we're sick of
your bad jokes, so chill.
Can't you give Aelita
a break for once?
You knew she'd believe you, right?
What can I say, Ulrich sweetie,
she's gonna have to adapt, isn't she?
It's a jungle out there.
You can say that again!
I'm looking at a
big baboon right now!
(LAUGHS)
Shut up, you!
Sissi's such a brat.
And to think you guys
actually kissed once.
Hey, cool it, huh.
That's ancient history.
So, you think the
owner of the Hermitage
and the science teacher
are the same person?
Well, let's face it, huh.
Finding two guys called Franz Hopper
in a radius of less than half a mile
would sure be a real coincidence.
Anyway, there's only
one way to be sure.
After history class, we have
a study period in the library.
What do you say we do a little research
in the Kadic Academy archives?
Good idea.
I'll go with you.
I don't think that's a good idea.
You already got into trouble
in the showers this morning.
if Jim catches you snooping
around in the archives,
you'll be suspended for sure.
Okay. See you later.
We'll meet you in the cafeteria.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
Are you alright, Aelita?
I can't get used to living here.
I had another nightmare last night.
The same one.
You haven't even been here for a week yet!
You'll see. You'll feel better in no time.
E, F, G, H…
H for Hopper.
(HUMMING)
Ah, shoot.
Shouldn't you be in class?
Well, children?
We're looking for um…a teacher!
Oh, really? Which one?
Misses Meyer.
Mister Charden!
(LAUGH NERVOUSLY)
Hopper, Hopper…
Bingo!
Err…come to think of it,
at this time of day, if you
can't find your teachers,
it probably means they're in class.
It's okay, guys!
I found Mrs. Hertz!
Mam.
(SIGHS)
Hey! What are you waiting for?
Come on, huh!
Will you move it?
Well, sweetie!
Franks and beans or
steak and potatoes?
Uh, well, uh…
Come on, hurry up!
We're starving over here!
Hmph.
Oh?
Our turn!
About time!
Boy, that was a close one.
Well?
No doubt about it.
I compared the teacher's signature
with the one on the property deed
I found on the internet.
They're the same.
Hmm.
What if we had a look
around the Hermitage
to find out more
about this teacher?
Good idea.
But…aren't we supposed to
meet Aelita in the cafeteria now?
It'll only take a minute.
She won't mind waiting a little.
Yumi!
So?
Going back to the great white north?
Why not?
At least I'd feel at home there!
Still looks as creepy as ever.
What are we looking for?
How should I know?
If this Franz Hopper guy
has anything to do with XANA,
maybe we'll find some information
about Aelita's virus for a start.
Well?
Not much. Physics textbooks.
Planck, Heisenberg, Schrödinger…
Hey!
What's this doing here?
"The Tunic Wars?"
What's that?
Punic, not tunic.
The war between the Romans
and the Carthaginians.
We studied it last year.
Don't you remember anything?
No.
You really are lame in history.
You see all these notes?
I'm sure Hopper wrote them.
Quiet, please. Where's Aelita Stones?
Jeremie, do you know
why Aelita isn't here?
Aelita? Huh!
Uh…huh?
Um…sorry, mam, I don't.
Well, I do, mam!
She went back to Canada!
Canada?
Yeah, that's what she told me!
She even said, "At least I
feel at home there."
Elizabeth, if you continue to
disrupt the class, I warn you,
I will send you to your father's office.
(mutters):
It's Sissi, not Elizabeth!
I hate being called Elizabeth!
Mam, um, I don't feel very well.
Can I please go to the infirmary?
Of course, Jeremie.
Can we take him?
Well, oh…
Oh, alright, then.
But don't dilly-dally!
Jeremie, wait! Hey!
Where are you going?
To the factory!
You think Aelita's there?
She told Sissi she was
going back to Canada.
I think she meant, "I'm going back
to the place I came from,"
which means Lyoko.
Okay. I found her.
She virtualized herself all on her own.
That's pretty weird.
Why would she do that?
Maybe she got homesick.
Does Yumi know?
I left her a message.
Get to the scanner room. Hurry!
Aelita, can you hear me?
Answer me!
Ah, Yumi!
I got the message
at the swimming pool.
What's going on?
Run to the scanner room.
Ulrich and Odd are already there.
I'll explain later.
Jeremie, help!
Aelita! Don't worry.
The others are on the way.
Transfer Ulrich.
Transfer Odd.
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner and virtualization!
Do you see her?
Not yet.
She's due north!
Let's go.
(PANTING)
Jeremie, I'm surrounded!
Hurry up! Aelita's fallen into a trap!
(SCREAMS)
Go ahead, Ulrich.
With your speed,
you'll get there first.
You're right.
Too late.
Krab.
There's another one behind you!
Okay. Battle stations.
Aelita's bought some time.
Your move, Odd.
I love this.
Hiyah!
Laser arrow!
Nice going, guys.
But hurry it up!
The bloks are catching up to Aelita.
What are you waiting for? Call us a taxi!
It's on the way.
Hurry, Jeremie!
Vehicle materialization.
Here we go!
The others are coming to get you.
(SCREAMS)
Aelita!
What? She's already gone?
She must really be mad at us.
This is no time for jokes, Odd.
I've lost Aelita from my screens.
You…you mean she's…
No! Uh, I doubt it.
I think she's disappeared
from the screens as if…
Wait.
What's going on?
Got it! I got a signal!
A very weak one, but…
Hey, that's strange.
Aelita's not in this sector anymore.
She's not in any sector, actually.
Wait.
Can you explain that a little better?
No. Not really.
Let's just say she's in
a sector…that doesn't exist.
A fifth sector.
Huh?
A fifth sector?
Have you gone bananas or what!
No. If I could just fix this thing!
Maybe I…
"Welcome to Carthage?"
(WHIRRING)
Is this gonna take long, Jeremie?
I hope not.
Uh-oh. Now things are
really starting to buzz.
Super sprint!
Jeremie, what are we doing?
Wait. I've got a little problem.
That's no biggie!
As long as it's not a biggie!
I need a password.
Something to do with Carthage, I think.
This is no time for a history lesson!
A history lesson!
That's exactly what I need!
That'd be too easy.
Laser arrow!
Hannibal…
Carthage general…
His father? No…
Hey, Jeremie!
Any day now!
Hannibal's sister? Salambo?
(MOANS)
The nemesis of Carthage?
No dice!
Whenever you're ready, Einstein!
Hey, you guys, I'm doing my best!
Jeremie, we're not gonna last much longer.
I'm sure I'm gonna get it!
Oh, no. I can't believe this.
I'm going around in circles!
"Welcome to Carthage!"
Let's see. You've got to
go into Carthage…
You have to defeat Carthage.
Who defeated the Carthaginians?
Scipio!
S-C-I-P-I-O!
Come on!
I can't believe it!
Hey, the hornets are calling it quits.
Come back, you cowards!
What's that ball doing there?
I think the codeword
Scipio made it appear.
Hey!
Whoa!
How did you do that, Jeremie?
Let's just say I got a little
help from Franz Hopper.
Welcome to sector five, everyone.
What does it look like?
A sphere that…
Uh…it's probably bad news.
Jeremie! Jeremie!
I think Aelita is being attacked
and time is almost up!
Can you guide us?
Take the footbridge behind you.
Hurry up! This is no time for sightseeing!
(SCREAMS)
Super sprint!
Hey, what's going on?
Uh…Jeremie, there's
this thing in here.
Destroy it! That thing is
taking away Aelita's memory!
Something weird's happening.
Oh, no! That can't be good!
Get out of there!
Got it.
Odd, beat it!
Just in time!
(PANTING)
Now, what?
Wait. I'm re-entering the code.
Scipio.
We've got your ticket out of here, Aelita.
And there you go.
I'm bringing you in right now.
Aelita, all you have to do
is get to the tower, and I'll
rematerialize you.
Materialization Yumi.
Materialization Odd.
Materialization Ulrich.
(SIGHS)
You should've seen it, Jeremie.
There were all these creepy things,
and in the middle, this kind of
huge jellyfish holding Aelita!
(GROWLS)
Can you imagine? That thing
was stealing my memory.
Yeah. One thing is sure --
XANA wants to get something
out of you, but what?
That's what we have to find out.
I can't wait to go back to the fifth sector.
There's so much to explore there.
I'll go with you.
It'll be totally awesome.
Whoa, not so fast!
I have to study it first!
For now, it's uncharted territory,
which means it could be
totally dangerous!
Um…you're not angry at me for
going back to Lyoko by myself?
I…I don't know what got into me.
I just needed to…
You don't have to explain, Aelita.
We understand what happened.
And we're not angry at all.
I promise to spend
more time with you.
Yeah! And if you want,
I'll teach you plenty of ways
to tell Sissi to go to--
Odd!
Do you know what your
filthy mutt did in the shower?
Oh!
What a pretty picture!
So, you've finally found
Misses Einstein!
Yeah, while you were taking
your third shower of the day.
Well, you know, Ulrich dear,
a beautiful flower like me
needs to be watered often!
You--
Yes, you never know!
You might just sprout a brain!
(LAUGHTER)
Morons!
I think you can give Odd lessons, Aelita.
You sure learn fast!
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO